<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>CIP4 xPrintTalkLib</title>

    <abstract>
      <para>This document describes the structure and functionality of CIP4
      xPrintTalkLib and how to use it. The library was written in Java and
      simplify dealing with PrintTalk messages. It provides methods for
      creation, modification and analyzing.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The major conceptual change in JDF 2.0 (or XJDF) is the technology
    does no longer attempts to model the entire job as one large "job ticket"
    but rather specifies an interchange format between two applications that
    are assumed to have an internal data model that is not necessarily based
    on JDF. Thus each JDF ticket specifies a single transaction between two
    parties. A single job may be modeled as one or more JDF
    transactions.</para>

    <para>This fact also requires a conceptual change of JDF and PrintTalk
    libraries as well. Among other things the focus of 1.x libraries is
    dealing with large XML files (XML files were used as data storage),
    managing concurrency file access (spawn and merge) and handling the
    workflow logic (references). Further there even are implemented some very
    common XML functionalities like creating Java objects from XSD Schema and
    so on.</para>

    <para>Remember, the fundamental concepts of JDF (and the library) were
    designed in the nineties. At this time XML was a very new technology and
    just a few early XML Tools already had existed. Further the XML technology
    itself was in a very early phase of development. So it was essential to
    include all this stuff mentioned getting JDF working.</para>

    <para>Over the last two decades XML has become very popular. Many tools
    were designed and many conceptual enhancements in XML has been done. For
    example one significant enhancement has been XPath. More details about the
    XPath W3C Standard later in this document or on the W3C website:
    http://www.w3.org/TR/xpath/.</para>

    <para>Due to the major change from JDF 1.x to JDF 2.0 a redesign of the
    JDF and PrintTalk libraries is strongly recommended. The new xJdf /
    xPrintTalk library now is based on commonly used libraries and
    technologies like the Apache or JAXB framework. Supplementary
    functionality which has been removed from JDF Specification no longer
    makes the library unnecessarily complex for reasons of backwards
    compatibility. The goal of xJdfLib is to provide a lightweight, up to date
    and easy to use library optimized for actual requirements. This document
    describes the concepts and the usage of the CIP4 xJdfLib.</para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>The xPrintTalk Library</title>

    <para>The CIP4 xPrintTalkLib Java Library is based on Java 7. The latest
    stable version is being published on the CIP4 Website on page “Technical
    Resources -&gt; Downloads -&gt; Internal Source”. Further xPrintTalkLib is
    an Apache Maven project. So the latest stable version also is available in
    the public Central Maven Repositroy:</para>

    <programlisting language="xml">&lt;dependency&gt;
    &lt;groupId&gt;org.cip4.lib.xprinttalk&lt;/groupId&gt;
    &lt;artifactId&gt;xPrintTalkLib&lt;/artifactId&gt;
    &lt;version&gt;0.3&lt;/version&gt;
&lt;/dependency&gt;</programlisting>

    <para>Early Next-Version-Snapshots of CIP4 xPrintTalkLib Library are being
    published in the public OSS Sonatype Snapshot Repository:</para>

    <programlisting language="xml">&lt;repository&gt;
    &lt;id&gt;SnapshotOSS&lt;/id&gt;
    &lt;name&gt;OSS Snapshot&lt;/name&gt;
    &lt;url&gt;https://oss.sonatype.org/content/repositories/snapshots/&lt;/url&gt;
    &lt;snapshots&gt;
        &lt;enabled&gt;true&lt;/enabled&gt;
    &lt;/snapshots&gt;
&lt;/repository&gt;</programlisting>

    <programlisting language="xml">&lt;dependency&gt;
    &lt;groupId&gt;org.cip4.lib.xprinttalk&lt;/groupId&gt;
    &lt;artifactId&gt;xPrintTalkLib&lt;/artifactId&gt;
    &lt;version&gt;0.4-SNAPSHOT&lt;/version&gt;
&lt;/dependency&gt;</programlisting>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Core Components</title>

    <para>The concepts are equal to xJdfLib. So please check this
    documentation.</para>
    
    <para>Specific Components: MilestoneBuilder.</para>
  </chapter>
</book>
